Inventory of the H. R. G. Howman papers
Hoover Institution Archives
H. R. G. Howman papers
1901-1982
83059
Hoover Institution Archives
6 manuscript boxes, 8 microfilm reels (2.35 linear feet)
Reports, minutes, memoranda, correspondence, legislation, notes, and printed matter relating to governmental administration of, and social and economic conditions in, Rhodesia (Zimbabwe).
Howman, H. R. G. (H. Roger G.), 1909-
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1983.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Deputy secretary, Ministry of Internal Affairs, Rhodesia.
Scope and Content of Collection
Reports, minutes, memoranda, correspondence, legislation, notes, and printed matter relating to governmental administration of, and social and economic conditions in, Rhodesia (Zimbabwe).
Zimbabwe--Economic conditions.; Zimbabwe--Politics and government.; Zimbabwe--Social conditions.
- J1 - J179: Legal and Social Position of Women (Box-folder 1: 1-2)
- F1 - F432: Chronological Papers on Emergence of Community Development Policy and the Reactivation of Agricultural[?] Extension, Home Economics and Natural Resources Board, 1960-1968 (Box-folder 1: 3-5)
- DD1 - DD413: Community Development Policy and Education (Box-folder 1: 6-8)
- DD414 - DD471: Community Development Policy and Education (Box-folder 2: 1)
- G563 - G584: Miscellaneous Political Papers, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 2: 2)
- H1 - H77: Commission de Cooperation Technique en Afrique au Sud du Sahara (CCTA) Conferences, 1953-1961 (Box-folder 2: 3)
- C1 - C495: The Germ and Evolution of the Concept of Community Development, 1948-1977 (Box-folder 2: 4-6)
- I1 - I251: Working Party D: Tribal Authority and the Land (Box-folder 2: 7-8)
- II1 - II114: Reports and Papers - James Green (Box-folder 2: 9)
- II115 - II261: Reports and Papers - James Green (Box-folder 3: 1)
- G191 - G358: Prime Minister's Directive of July 1965 (Box-folder 3: 2)
- A1 - A688: Personal Paper Collection, 1934-1963 September (Box-folder 3: 3-6)
- A689 - A737: Personal Paper Collection, 1934-1963 September (Box-folder 4: 1)
- G359 - G562: The Vote - Domboshawa Indaba (Box-folder 4: 2)
- D1- D152: Community Development Policy and Health (Box-folder 4: 3)
- C496 - C924: CD Vol II, 1962-1977 (Box-folder 4: 4-6)
- AA1 - AA168: Personal Paper Collection, 1962 November - 1969 September (Box-folder 4: 7)
- AA169 - AA275: Personal Paper Collection, 1962 November - 1969 September (Box-folder 5: 1)
- AA276 - AA350: 1965-1968 (Box-folder 5: 2)
- AA351 - AA555 (Box-folder 5: 3)
- X1 - X160: Personal Papers, 1970-1983 (Box-folder 5: 4)
- B1 - B446: Personal Paper Collection, 1970-1983 (Box-folder 5: 5-7)
- B447 - B718: Personal Paper Collection, 1970-1983 (Box-folder 6: 1-2)
- G1 - G190: Arguments on Local Government; Papers on P. A[?]'s Directive of 1965; Papers on "The Vote" and the Domboshawa Indaba; Miscellaneous papers - Patterson Commission, Chief's Tour (Box-folder 6: 3)
- Register of microfilmed materials (Box-folder 6: 4)
  Note
  Not all items listed in this register may have been filmed.
- Microfilm (Reels 1-8)
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains a microfilm copy of H. R. G. Howman papers that are not held at the Hoover Institution. These papers include: Government Committees and Enquiries, 1951-1962; Subject File, 1944-1976; Confidential and Unpublished Reports and Memoranda, 1928-1971; Tribal Areas of Rhodesia Research Foundation (T. A. R. R. F.), 1967-1980; Speeches and Writings, 1949-1974; University Reports Etc., 1971-1980; and Publications, 1901-1975.
  For a more detailed description, see the register located in Box 6. Please note not all items listed in the register may have been filmed.